<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meditation on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meditation on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/meditation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brain as a Neural Net</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/brain-as-a-neural-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/brain-as-a-neural-net/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re still struggling to figure out exactly what Consciousness is. One theory that I kinda like (although I have no sense of how correct it is) is that consciousness is a way of approximating the base reality. There is too much data coming in through our senses, and it is impossible for every part of the brain to process everything at the same time. So it creates an approximation, which is perceived in the form of consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Meditate</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/why-i-meditate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/why-i-meditate/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Do not try to use what you learn from Buddhism to be a Buddhist; use it to be a better whatever-you-already-are.&amp;quot; &amp;ndash; Dalai Lama    Mental Health
This is the most obvious reason to meditate. If you think of your mind as another organ, then just as you need to keep your muscles healthy so too your mind. It&amp;rsquo;s not entirely clear to me what a healthy mind means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Issues With Meditation</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/my-issues-with-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/my-issues-with-meditation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m quite sold on Meditation and do it pretty regularly. In a separate post, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about what about Meditation interests me. Here, I want to collect all the things about the cult of Meditation that offend me in some way. I&amp;rsquo;m mostly doing this for my own clarification so that I can articulate my concerns precisely and then move on and focus on the positive aspects of Meditation.
 First the obvious stuff:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feelings</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/feelings/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a radical idea in Robert Wrights&amp;rsquo;s Why Buddhism is True. Our last big phase of evolution happened during the hunter-gatherer phase and we haven&amp;rsquo;t yet evolved to adapt to the modern world (this is not the radical idea). I encountered this fact for the first time in Yuval Harari&amp;rsquo;s Sapiens, where he claims that humans have been hunter-gatherers for a far longer time than we have been farmers and non-nomads.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
