<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sci-fi on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/sci-fi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sci-fi on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/sci-fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Umbrella Academy</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/theumbrellaacademy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/theumbrellaacademy/</guid>
      <description>I love the adaptations of graphic novels. I love contrasting and comparing the two art forms and seeing how they bring out completely different aspects of the same story.
The comics are a collection of short stories whereas the series is closer to a novel. In the comics, the characters have very singular personality traits. They are caricatures and not recognizable as human beings. All of them are extremely damaged and there is a singular desire or a past trauma that determines their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/dark/</guid>
      <description>I have always loved sci-fi. I love sci-fi more than I love actual science. Sci-fi is hardly ever about science. It is imaginative and fantastic. It is always about people. For exactly this reason, Dark is a fantastic sci-fi. In its three seasons, the lives of its handful characters get deeply and inextricably intertwined and the actors performing these roles give candid performances that makes all the chaos thoroughly believable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Astra</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/movies/ad-astra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/movies/ad-astra/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the obvious. Brad Pitt has managed to give the performance of a lifetime in Ad Astra. There are many scenes in the movie when he just emotes, there is nothing else going on in the entire frame, just him in focus with melancholic colors of space and science providing the stage. You can see his expressions go through an array of subtle but powerful changes, a slight tremor in an eyebrow, a hesitant blink, a slight quivering of the lips, a surreptitious teardrop that betrays the stoic facade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Doll</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/russian-doll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/russian-doll/</guid>
      <description>Russian Doll is a modern day interpretation of the Groundhog Day. While the theme itself is quite cliché and played out, Russian Doll brings in Netflix&amp;rsquo;s awesome production to create a mostly enjoyable series. With eight short episodes this is basically the length of a long movie, perfect length which prevents the series from feeling draggy. It&amp;rsquo;s short enough that it does not have to delve deeply into philosophy but long enough for the characters to evolve organically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Body Problem</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/three-body-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/three-body-problem/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Weakness and ignorance are not barriers to survival, but arrogance is.&#34; -Three Body Problem  Of the Three Body Problem trilogy, I immensely enjoyed reading the first book and had to drag my way across the other two.
The first book has a very beautiful structure. It is intensely gripping with very honest, well-formed characters, it jumps across various timelines introducing us to the Chinese cultural revolution along the way, has a whodunit mystery, creates great sci-fi worlds - a complete package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuromancer</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/neuromancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/neuromancer/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The sky above the port was the color of television, tuned to a dead channel.&#34; -Neuromancer  I always knew that The Matrix had to have found it&amp;rsquo;s concepts from some book, it was too revolutionary a movie to have spawned out of nothing. And I finally found it - Neuromancer, the archetypal cyberpunk novel.
This is probably the hardest and simultaneously the most riveting sci-fi novel I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendezvous with Rama</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/rendezvous-with-rama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/rendezvous-with-rama/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The human race has to live with its conscience. Whatever the Hermians argue, survival is not everything.&#34; -Rendezvous with Rama  I&amp;rsquo;m biased towards space novels. Reading about space travel and stars and planets and contemplating the huge vastness and emptiness always fills me with a sense of indescribable wonder, bliss, and humility.
Arthur Clarke&amp;rsquo;s Rendezvous with Rama is a space poetry. It starts with a simple premise of an alien object (Rama) suddenly appearing in the solar system and humans venturing out to explore it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gods Themselves</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/the-gods-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/the-gods-themselves/</guid>
      <description>In the opening scene of Nolan&amp;rsquo;s Prestige, Michael Caine explains what a magic trick consists of - a pledge, a turn, and the hardest part - the Prestige. This is what Asimov&amp;rsquo;s stories are like. He starts with an ordinary world with something slightly extraordinary about it, takes you around on a tour through the wonders of the world to distract you and slowly builds up the mystery in plain sight, until the big reveal in the final act.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
