<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Harris on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/sam-harris/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sam Harris on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/sam-harris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waking Up App</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/waking-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/waking-up/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid reader and there are quite a few books that have made me completely restructure my life and thinking. This is a relatively new phenomenon. It is only when I started facing a lot of uncertainty and conflict that I started to read and think more seriously and let what I read change me. These books have not been about facts or history or science or philosophy but rather about introspection and thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repetitive thoughts</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/repetitive-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/repetitive-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I become aware of some chaos in my mind, I try to follow my chain of thoughts to the source. This makes &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; just how tenuous and ridiculous most connections from one thought to the next are. The fickle mind crosses the flimsiest of bridges simply to fulfill its own need of constantly thinking something. Once your mind realizes just how ridiculous this all is and how embarrassing the source of all this chaos is, it automatically calms down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do thoughts come from?</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/where-do-thoughts-come-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/where-do-thoughts-come-from/</guid>
      <description>I had been thinking on and off about free will for some time now. To anyone who has some time to think, the pandemic is bound to raise some serious questions about control and free will. The following marathon conversation between Lex Fridman and Sam Harris rekindled my interest in the subject.
  Do humans have free will?
At the most fundamental level, the answer has to be no as we are all bound by the laws of physics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
