<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>non-fiction on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/non-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in non-fiction on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Gene: An Intimate History</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/gene/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/gene/</guid>
      <description>This book is the story of the birth, growth, and future of one of the most powerful and dangerous ideas in the history of science: the “gene,” the fundamental unit of heredity, and the basic unit of all biological information.
 When you read good books, you start immersing yourself into the world of its words. Everytime you open its pages a parallel universe emerges for you transgress. And when the book is really good, you leave a different person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisionist History</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/revisionisthistory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/revisionisthistory/</guid>
      <description>Every day for the past few months I would excitedly look forward to my work commute across this dreary city; I was listening to Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s Revisionist History. As I was fiddling around with the various podcast apps trying to find one that I could use while driving without getting myself into an accident (whatever happened to intuitive design?), I accidentally started listening to the series in the reverse order. Fortuitously for me, these episodes were The Queen of Cuba and The Obscure Virus Club and they got me hooked real fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Talk About When I Talk About Running</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/running-murakami/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/running-murakami/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Most runners run not because they want to live longer, but because they want to live life to the fullest. If you’re going to while away the years, it’s far better to live them with clear goals and fully alive than in a fog, and I believe running helps you do that. Exerting yourself to the fullest within your individual limits: that’s the essence of running, and a metaphor for life—and for me, for writing as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bird by Bird</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/bird-by-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/bird-by-bird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have much truth to express unless we have gone into those rooms and closets and woods and abysses that we were told not go in to. When we have gone in and looked around for a long while, just breathing and finally taking it in &amp;ndash; then we will be able to speak in our own voice and to stay in the present moment. And that moment is home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Checklist Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/checklist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/checklist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Man is fallible, but maybe men are less so.&#34; -The Checklist Manifesto  It is such a simple idea, and yet so hard to follow. When your work is complicated, involves serious teamwork, needs to be done in a time critical manner, is prone to errors of oversight; make a checklist. Follow it diligently, and upgrade it frequently. The purpose of a checklist is not to replace human thought, but to take care of the trivialities so that the mind can focus on more important things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/gtd-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/gtd-method/</guid>
      <description>These are some notes I took from the book Getting Things Done by David Allen. Let me first start with the cons of the book. First the book is tediously repetitive, while some repetition is good to drill the concepts deep in your mind, the book overdoes it. Second, the book is clearly intended for people who&amp;rsquo;ve white collar jobs, mostly managers and executives.
But that does not mean that you cannot gatecrash the party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Area of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/an-area-of-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/an-area-of-darkness/</guid>
      <description>An Area of Darkness is a disturbing pessimistic novel written by V.S. Naipaul about his first visit to India in 1962. This was India not too long after the Independence with it&amp;rsquo;s freshly minted Constitution, trying to make a transition from an English past to an Indian future. Naipaul shares the sentiments of West, the tone of the book is not unlike Slumdog Millionaire (a very unpopular movie in India).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking, Fast &amp; Slow</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:40:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/thinking-fast-and-slow/</guid>
      <description>Thinking, Fast and Slow in a life changing book written by our lord and savior Daniel Kahneman, Danny Kanny.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book you should drop everything that you&amp;rsquo;re doing and start reading it right away. It is extremely well written and easy to read, with short chapters and lucid Hemingway-styled language lacking any pretentiousness.
Danny Kanny posits a two system model for our minds. The faster system which is also the system truly in charge, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
