<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Series on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Series on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Midnight Diner</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/midnight-diner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/midnight-diner/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;When people finish their day and hurry home, my day starts. My diner is open from midnight to seven in the morning. They call it &amp;ldquo;Midnight Diner&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s all I have on my menu. But I make whatever customers request as long as I have the ingredients for it. That&amp;rsquo;s my policy. Do I even have customers? More than you would expect.&amp;quot;
   This is the most wholesome TV series ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stranger (Korean)</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/strangerkorean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/strangerkorean/</guid>
      <description>Memories of Murder, which is a Korean movie, is one of my favorite detective movies. I like Korean movies a lot, so I decided to try out some Korean TV. And now Season 1 of Stranger, a Korean series, is one of my favorite detective series!
The series is not innovative or unique in any way. But it is very well executed. The characters are diverse, likeable, and well-developed, the cast is great with genuinely good acting, the story is tight with just enough melodrama, every episode ends in a cliff hanger, the pacing is perfect, there are no miracles or accidents, nothing hidden from the audience - whatever the protagonist knows the audience knows, thrilling soundtrack; a textbook example of how to make a good detective show, a masterpiece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peaky Blinders</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/peakyblinders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/peakyblinders/</guid>
      <description>Of late, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost the patience to watch long TV shows. Surprisingly, the pandemic made me want to watch series even less and instead I wasted a lot of time on YouTube watching short British comedy clips. I was then pleasantly surprised when I got hooked on to watching Peaky Blinders on Netflix.
Growing up reading primarily British authors, I have developed some fascination with their history. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt that their history is intertwined with India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Umbrella Academy</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/theumbrellaacademy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/theumbrellaacademy/</guid>
      <description>I love the adaptations of graphic novels. I love contrasting and comparing the two art forms and seeing how they bring out completely different aspects of the same story.
The comics are a collection of short stories whereas the series is closer to a novel. In the comics, the characters have very singular personality traits. They are caricatures and not recognizable as human beings. All of them are extremely damaged and there is a singular desire or a past trauma that determines their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/dark/</guid>
      <description>I have always loved sci-fi. I love sci-fi more than I love actual science. Sci-fi is hardly ever about science. It is imaginative and fantastic. It is always about people. For exactly this reason, Dark is a fantastic sci-fi. In its three seasons, the lives of its handful characters get deeply and inextricably intertwined and the actors performing these roles give candid performances that makes all the chaos thoroughly believable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haji/Giri</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/haji-giri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/haji-giri/</guid>
      <description>I am fascinated by Japan, the country that has produced Naruto, Bleach, Akira, Ghost in the shell, Murakami, Ishiguro, Miyazaki and so much more. An inward-looking, closed island riddled with lost youth and a dying population that has somehow managed to preserve its culture in the present and has had so much influence on the world. It is mystical, fantastic, spiritual, and simultaneously one of the biggest purveyors of porn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisionist History</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/revisionisthistory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/revisionisthistory/</guid>
      <description>Every day for the past few months I would excitedly look forward to my work commute across this dreary city; I was listening to Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s Revisionist History. As I was fiddling around with the various podcast apps trying to find one that I could use while driving without getting myself into an accident (whatever happened to intuitive design?), I accidentally started listening to the series in the reverse order. Fortuitously for me, these episodes were The Queen of Cuba and The Obscure Virus Club and they got me hooked real fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Doll</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/russian-doll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/series/russian-doll/</guid>
      <description>Russian Doll is a modern day interpretation of the Groundhog Day. While the theme itself is quite cliché and played out, Russian Doll brings in Netflix&amp;rsquo;s awesome production to create a mostly enjoyable series. With eight short episodes this is basically the length of a long movie, perfect length which prevents the series from feeling draggy. It&amp;rsquo;s short enough that it does not have to delve deeply into philosophy but long enough for the characters to evolve organically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
