<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is an Idea?</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/what-is-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/what-is-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, on an evening of drinking and philosophizing, a friend asked me this question and I did not have any answer then.
Chris Anderson&amp;rsquo;s video about giving TED talks kept popping into my mind; I remembered it mostly for the pretty visuals it had representing what an idea is. But I could not extract out an exact definition from it. Just this morning, as I was reading Siddhartha Mukherjee&amp;rsquo;s book about genes, the answer popped into my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy &amp; Me</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/philosophy-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/philosophy-and-me/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m using the term Philosophy in an ill-defined manner. For me, it means something like an analytical tool or a way of thinking, and not a subject studied in universities.
I grew up with a deep distaste for Philosophy, thanks to having seen the perils of eastern philosophies first hand, and also thanks to the disdain that physicists like Feynman (whom I greatly admire) showed toward the subject. However, of late, my attitude towards it has changed completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/know-thyself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/know-thyself/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important lessons of Thinking, Fast and Slow is that our brains are unable to analyze real world data objectively. We alter our memories and retroactively modify our experiences to fit a story. The only solution to this is to keep records and to trust the data.
For me, the two most easily measurable resources are internet usage and money. After reading the book I was sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being honest with myself about these things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
