<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditation on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditation on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/acceptance/</guid>
      <description>One of the often quoted, somewhat grandiose term from mindfulness is that of Acceptance. You&amp;rsquo;re supposed to &amp;ldquo;accept the current moment&amp;rdquo; for what it is.
I was under the impression that I was doing this already and that I had pretty much figured it out. I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty chill guy who usually does not worry too much about future developments. I am good at being ok with any way things turn out, and tend not to get too stressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain as a Neural Net</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/brain-as-a-neural-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/brain-as-a-neural-net/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re still struggling to figure out exactly what Consciousness is. One theory that I kinda like (although I have no sense of how correct it is) is that consciousness is a way of approximating the base reality. There is too much data coming in through our senses, and it is impossible for every part of the brain to process everything at the same time. So it creates an approximation, which is perceived in the form of consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Meditate</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/why-i-meditate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/why-i-meditate/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Do not try to use what you learn from Buddhism to be a Buddhist; use it to be a better whatever-you-already-are.&amp;quot; &amp;ndash; Dalai Lama    Mental Health
This is the most obvious reason to meditate. If you think of your mind as another organ, then just as you need to keep your muscles healthy so too your mind. It&amp;rsquo;s not entirely clear to me what a healthy mind means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Issues With Meditation</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/my-issues-with-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/my-issues-with-meditation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m quite sold on Meditation and do it pretty regularly. In a separate post, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about what about Meditation interests me. Here, I want to collect all the things about the cult of Meditation that offend me in some way. I&amp;rsquo;m mostly doing this for my own clarification so that I can articulate my concerns precisely and then move on and focus on the positive aspects of Meditation.
 First the obvious stuff:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feelings</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/feelings/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a radical idea in Robert Wrights&amp;rsquo;s Why Buddhism is True. Our last big phase of evolution happened during the hunter-gatherer phase and we haven&amp;rsquo;t yet evolved to adapt to the modern world (this is not the radical idea). I encountered this fact for the first time in Yuval Harari&amp;rsquo;s Sapiens, where he claims that humans have been hunter-gatherers for a far longer time than we have been farmers and non-nomads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waking Up App</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/waking-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/waking-up/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid reader and there are quite a few books that have made me completely restructure my life and thinking. This is a relatively new phenomenon. It is only when I started facing a lot of uncertainty and conflict that I started to read and think more seriously and let what I read change me. These books have not been about facts or history or science or philosophy but rather about introspection and thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repetitive thoughts</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/repetitive-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/repetitive-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I become aware of some chaos in my mind, I try to follow my chain of thoughts to the source. This makes &amp;ldquo;me&amp;rdquo; just how tenuous and ridiculous most connections from one thought to the next are. The fickle mind crosses the flimsiest of bridges simply to fulfill its own need of constantly thinking something. Once your mind realizes just how ridiculous this all is and how embarrassing the source of all this chaos is, it automatically calms down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do thoughts come from?</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/where-do-thoughts-come-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/where-do-thoughts-come-from/</guid>
      <description>I had been thinking on and off about free will for some time now. To anyone who has some time to think, the pandemic is bound to raise some serious questions about control and free will. The following marathon conversation between Lex Fridman and Sam Harris rekindled my interest in the subject.
  Do humans have free will?
At the most fundamental level, the answer has to be no as we are all bound by the laws of physics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unstructured Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/unstructured-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/unstructured-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I often take long walks and think about things while walking. Being a mathematician, I have a tendency to figure things out in my head. While this works great most of the time, there are occasions when this causes me a great deal of anxiety and frustration. As life becomes more complex, the latter situation is only becoming more frequent.
I used to think that this has to do with overthinking but I no longer believe that it is possible for the brain to overthink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing Your Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/observing-your-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/observing-your-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You are right, Watson,&amp;rdquo; said he. &amp;ldquo;It does seem a most preposterous way of settling a dispute.&amp;quot;
  &amp;ldquo;Most preposterous!&amp;rdquo; I exclaimed, and then suddenly realizing how he had echoed the inmost thought of my soul, I sat up in my chair and stared at him in blank amazement&amp;rdquo; - Adventures of the Cardboard Box
 Sherlock Holmes might have been able to predict the thoughts of Dr. Watson but I have found out that predicting my own thoughts is enough of a challenge for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday Meditation</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/everyday-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/meditation/everyday-meditation/</guid>
      <description>Meditation sucks at first. It sucks badly for a long long time. It is SO bad, SO sucky. The harder you try the more you suck at it. But it is hubris to assume that you would naturally be an expert at it. I have been trying it on and off unsuccessfully for many years. Only now, thanks to the lockdown, I have finally been able to do it consistently and have started liking it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
