<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Murakami on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/murakami/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Murakami on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/murakami/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1Q84</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/1q84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/1q84/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;If you can&amp;rsquo;t understand it without an explanation, you can&amp;rsquo;t understand it with an explanation.&amp;quot;
- 1Q84
 What most surprised me about 1Q84 is that I actually liked reading it! I have read enough Murakami that as I was reading the book I knew that he was not going to explain anything and yet I did not feel frustrated. I have developed a taste for his writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Talk About When I Talk About Running</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/running-murakami/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/running-murakami/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Most runners run not because they want to live longer, but because they want to live life to the fullest. If you’re going to while away the years, it’s far better to live them with clear goals and fully alive than in a fog, and I believe running helps you do that. Exerting yourself to the fullest within your individual limits: that’s the essence of running, and a metaphor for life—and for me, for writing as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Wood</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/norwegian-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/norwegian-wood/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What happens when people open their hearts?&amp;quot;
&amp;ldquo;They get better.” - Norwegian Wood
 Norwegian Wood is a teenage love story/coming of age story set mainly in Tokyo and the mountains of Kyoto. The name derives from the eponymous song by the Beatles.
I have very mixed feelings about the book. On one hand, the book has a very pulp feeling to it. There are too many sex scenes described with unnecessary details (the scenes aren&amp;rsquo;t even interesting, just teenagers jerking each other off) and every conversation between the protagonists eventually converges towards sex, love, and masturbation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
