<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is an Idea?</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/what-is-an-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/what-is-an-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, on an evening of drinking and philosophizing, a friend asked me this question and I did not have any answer then.
Chris Anderson&amp;rsquo;s video about giving TED talks kept popping into my mind; I remembered it mostly for the pretty visuals it had representing what an idea is. But I could not extract out an exact definition from it. Just this morning, as I was reading Siddhartha Mukherjee&amp;rsquo;s book about genes, the answer popped into my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy &amp; Me</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/philosophy-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/random/philosophy/philosophy-and-me/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m using the term Philosophy in an ill-defined manner. For me, it means something like an analytical tool or a way of thinking, and not a subject studied in universities.
I grew up with a deep distaste for Philosophy, thanks to having seen the perils of eastern philosophies first hand, and also thanks to the disdain that physicists like Feynman (whom I greatly admire) showed toward the subject. However, of late, my attitude towards it has changed completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fall</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/the-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/the-fall/</guid>
      <description>With every Camus book there are two major problems:
 The writing is purposefully contrived, possibly lost in translation from French. The meaning is purposefully contrived, possibly lost in translation from French.  In spite of this, I just cannot get enough of his books. He is the most enlightened person I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read.
The Fall is the story of a benevolent lawyer who is always going out of his ways to help others, a hugely successful lawyer who offers his services to the poor for free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crime and Punishment</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/crime-and-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/crime-and-punishment/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What do you think, would not one tiny crime be wiped out by thousands of good deeds?&amp;quot;
 Crime and Punishment is Dostoevsky&amp;rsquo;s criticism of naive rationalism, utilitarianism, and armchair philosophizing. For such a boring topic, this is a surprisingly fun read. Adhering to his own criticism, Dostoevsky does not take to prophesying and making grand philosophical arguments about the pros and cons of communism but instead weaves an interesting and entertaining narrative of what might happen if one were to take rationalism to its extreme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Knowing</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/not-knowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/not-knowing/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s something I have been thinking about a lot lately, thanks mostly to my being on the internet almost constantly. We live in a world where we can just google the answer to many of the questions that arise in day-to-day life. This is great in that it is harder to lie about things and this increases equity and transparency in that one does not have to trust another person&amp;rsquo;s word blindly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myth of Sisyphus</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/myth-of-sisyphus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/notes/books/myth-of-sisyphus/</guid>
      <description>“Man stands face to face with the irrational. He feels within him his longing for happiness and for reason. The absurd is born of this confrontation between the human need and the unreasonable silence of the world.”  The central question, says Camus, is that of suicide. If you are going to die one day, why not just kill yourself now?
Starting from here, he develops the philosophy of the absurd.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
