<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lockdown Diaries on PostDoc Problems</title>
    <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lockdown Diaries on PostDoc Problems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>At the Dentist</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/dentist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/dentist/</guid>
      <description>For the lack of better things to do, I have been visiting my dentist lately. The x-ray machine they had looked like it came straight out of the Starship Enterprise. While I was getting my teeth drilled, even though I was sweating profusely and barely managed to not shit in my pants, I could not but marvel at the fact that I had my tooth drilled and filled in less than an hour!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/sleep/</guid>
      <description>I have heard Matthew Walker talk about sleep, a lot. But I never really took him seriously. I find him preachy and his talks are always exaggerated. The first time I got really curious about sleep is when I heard this talk:   One of the silver linings of this depressing lockdown is that this has given me a lot of time to reflect and introspect, look inwards as they say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP conferences</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/rip-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/rip-conferences/</guid>
      <description>A conference is a good concept in theory but entirely absurd in practice. You take a complete break from your daily life, delegate all your responsibilities to others, hope that your house and your class does not burn down in your absence and head off to some obscure place to listen to strangers give talks on mildly interesting topics. Something like 90% of the speakers I’ve encountered are bad speakers. I mostly sit in the back and do my own thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Knowing</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/not-knowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/not-knowing/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s something I have been thinking about a lot lately, thanks mostly to my being on the internet almost constantly. We live in a world where we can just google the answer to many of the questions that arise in day-to-day life. This is great in that it is harder to lie about things and this increases equity and transparency in that one does not have to trust another person&amp;rsquo;s word blindly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cataclysm Sentence</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/the-cataclysm-sentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/the-cataclysm-sentence/</guid>
      <description>It was Thanksgiving Day and we had gotten lucky. There were three of us driving to the Grand Canyon and exactly three others had canceled their reservations. Our bags packed with food and water, enough to last a couple of days, overjoyed, we started descending the canyon.
You walk and you walk, in the sweltering sun, a few minutes pass, then a few hours. The throngs start dwindling and slowly you forget the “rest of the world”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No New News</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/no-new-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/no-new-news/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the lockdown, first thing in the morning, before I can even open my groggy eyes, I check the news. But no more.
There is a concept I first heard about on Joe Rogan&amp;rsquo;s podcast which was an eye-opener. We have our &amp;ldquo;circle of control&amp;rdquo; and our &amp;ldquo;circle of concern&amp;rdquo;. They occasionally overlap but mostly they don&amp;rsquo;t. We tend to spend far too much time roaming in our circle of concern and far too little in our circle of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockdown Diaries</title>
      <link>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/lockdown-diaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://apurvanakade.github.io/blog/journal/lockdown-diaries/lockdown-diaries/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to write enough the past year. That&amp;rsquo;s because I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to read enough the past year.
Poem.
The joys of teaching at a public university have been a tad too satiating for me, but they have prepared me well for this new social distancing lifestyle. This concept of being stuck in your home because the outside might kill you is nothing foreign to Canada. Here, we call it Winter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
